Guide to the New York State College of Human Ecology records, 1900-2017
Cornell University, New York State College of Human Ecology records,
- Series IX. Videos
  - Albany Seminar- this is a dress rehearsal of the seminar entitled "Supporting Children in an Era of Welfare Reform" that was to happen the following week at the Family Policy center in Albany, 1996-10-16; V-562 (Box 48)
  - Meinig Symposium- speaker from the World Food Program- Senior Humanitarian Officer speaks - Part I, 1995-10-27; V-98251 (Box 48)
  - Meinig Symposium- speaker from the World Food Program- Senior Humanitarian Officer speaks - Part II, 1995-10-27; V-563 (Box 48)
  - Janet Clay White Lecture- entitled "A View From the Inside Out: Participants' Views of Food Assistance", 1995-09-28; V-6939, V-9372 (Box 115)
  - Janet Clay White Lecture- Marci K. Campbell - PicTel Conference, 2000-10-20; V-7092 (Box 115)
  - Janet Clay White Lecture- entitled "The Future of Human Nutrition" by Dr. Kim Travers, V-564, V-9371 (Box 115)
  - Kyoritsu World- Junior College in Japan- Cornell (CHE) is a sister school as of 1997, 2000-12; V-565 (Box 115)
  - Kyoritsu World- Junior College in Japan- Cornell (CHE) is a sister school, 2000-12; V-566 (Box 115)
  - "Healthy Families, Healthy Communities"- February 2001- building supportive policies, 2001-02; V-567 (Box 115)
  - "Statutory Colleges at Cornell: Service to the State, Nation, and the World", 1992-10; V-568 (Box 115)
  - Endowed Chair- Cindy Noble, Ethel Samson and Carol, V-569 (Box 115)
  - Celebrating 25 Years as Human Ecology, 2000-12; V-570 (Box 115)
  - Dean Francille Firebaugh- Retirement reception, 1998-09-25; V-571 (Box 115)
  - Human Ecology Strategic Planning Talk- discussion of university's organizational fit with its contemporary environment, 1994-09-08; V-572 (Box 115)
  - Tribute to Francille Firebaugh, V-573 (Box 115)
  - Tribute to Francille Firebaugh (second copy), V-9373 (Box 48)
  - Skipa Documentary: "Streets of Suffering"- Human Ecology student, Philippe Patker, class of 1995- went to Zimbabwe to study its history, culture and politics- founder of Skipa (Street Kids in Performing Arts), 1996-04-24; V-574 (Box 115)
  - "Changing Expectations of Faculty Roles and Responsibilities" part 3 of 6 part series examining the role of land-grant universities in the 21st century-video conference held at Clemson, 1997-11-04; V-575 (Box 115)
  - "Families in Crisis"- Symposium with Francille Firebaugh, 1994-09-26; V-576 (Box 115)
  - "Not in My School, Not in My Community"- video conference done in response to tragedy in Littleton, Colorado- Dean Firebaugh, Prof. Jim Garbarino were on tape, 1999-05-26; V-577 (Box 116)
  - Why Some Children Seem to Misreport Events- video conference with Professor Steven Ceci-two tapes, 1999-04-27; V-578, V-579 (Box 116)
  - Harlem Literacy Project, V-585 (Box 116)
  - Learnings from Essex Street, V-586 (Box 48)
  - Human Ecology Faculty in the News, V-587 (Box 116)
  - College of Human Ecology, V-646 (Box 116)
  - Strategic Planning Conference, 1994-09-08; V-647 (Box 116)
  - "Education for Social Justice: El Puente"-Luis Garden Acosta and Francos Lucerna the ISCOL Family Program for Leadership Development in Public Service, 2002-09-25; V-792 (Box 116)
  - "Unravelling the Gender Knot"-Dr. Allen G. Johnson, 2003-11-21; V-793 (Box 116)
  - Mini digital video cassette of closed North Wing - MVR - Roof through Second Floor, 2001-07; V-7093 (Box 116)
  - Mini digital video cassette of closed North Wing - First Floor through Ground Floor Administration Offices, 2003-07; V-7094 (Box 116)
  - Mini digital video cassette of closed North Wing - Ground Floor Administration Offices through Basement and Sub-Basement, 2003-07; V-7095 (Box 116)
  - "Valuing Our Past, Creating Our Future", 1991-04; V-794 (Box 116)
    This film celebrates the centennial of the college and discusses the history of the College of Human Ecology, formally the College of Home Economics.
    Project participants include Nancy Tomes from SUNY Stoneybrook, Patsy Brannon, Jerome Ziegler, Francille Firebaugh and Jean Failing.
  - "Valuing Our Past, Creating Our Future" - copy of video V-794, 1991-04; DVD-1009 (Box 116)
  - "Iscol Family Program For Leadership Development in Public Service, A Harder Thing: Discovering My Work in East Harlem - Ivan Hageman", V-1081 (Box 116)
  - "Iscol Family Program For Leadership Development in Public Service, The Light of Conscience: How a Simple Act Can Change Your Life By Bill Shore", 2004-09; V-1082 (Box 116)
- Series X: Publications and Reports
  - Newspaper Articles Concerning the College, 1969-1975 (Box 105, Folder 22)
  - Media Coverage:Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1992-1995 (Box 105, Folder 23)
  - Media Coverage: Students, 1985-1994 (Box 105, Folder 24)
  - Profile of the New York State College of Human Ecology, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Administration: An Administrative Guide to the College of Human Ecology, 1974 (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Some People You Should Know in the College of Human Ecology, 1974 (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Film Guide-"An Investment in Tomorrow", 1970-1979 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Long Range Plan for the College, 1971 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Programming Document for the Cornell Early Childhood Center Program, undated (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - "Women in Midlife Crises" - conference - Dialogue Newsletter, 1976 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Publication-"The Exchange", 1978-1981 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Address to Annual Meeting of Administrators of Home Economics-Jerome Ziegler, 1979 (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - Bulletins prepared by faculty in various college departments, 1980-1989 (Box 70, Folder 24)
  - Newsletter from Placement Office- "Openings", 1981 (Box 105, Folder 54)
  - Counseling and Advising Services-Review, 1982 (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - Curriculum Task Group, 1982 (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - External Image Task Force-"The CHE: the Decade Ahead" (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - Faculty Task Force-Final Report, 1982 (Box 70, Folder 13)
  - Placement Report, 1983 (Box 70, Folder 14)
  - "New Looks", 1985 (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Report on Efforts to Improve Undergraduate Instruction, 1985 (Box 106, Folder 40)
  - Report by Ad Hoc Committee on College Aging Program, 1986-04 (Box 106, Folder 41)
  - Proposal-Concentration in Aging/Gerontology, 1988 (Box 70, Folder 16)
  - College Resource Planning, 1988 (Box 70, Folder 17)
  - Cornell University Housing Program/Research Center, 1989 (Box 70, Folder 18)
  - Proposal to establish an Archive of Human Ecology/Design produced by Research and Design Institute, 1966-1983, 1989 (Box 70, Folder 19)
  - Research Manual, 1987, 1989 (Box 70, Folder 20)
  - Faculty Sourcebook, 1989 (Box 70, Folder 20)
  - "Securing the Future", 1990 (Box 106, Folder 42)
  - CHE International Task Force-"Small World; Large Vision", 1991 (Box 70, Folder 21)
  - College's Accomplishments and Concerns, 1991-1999 (Box 70, Folder 22)
  - Strategic Planning Reports - Foundations of Excellence, 1994-08, 1994-10 (Box 106, Folder 49)
  - Strategic Planning Update, 1997-10 (Box 106, Folder 50)
  - Impacts- Cornell addresses contemporary issues, 1997-1999, 2002, 2008 (Box 88, Folder 18)
  - Impacts- Cornell addresses contemporary issues, 2000-2002 (Box 88, Folder 19)
  - Report on Endowed Funds, 1996-1998 (Box 106, Folder 43)
  - Report on Endowed Funds, 1998-1999 (Box 106, Folder 44)
  - Report on Endowed Funds, 1999-2000 (Box 106, Folder 45)
  - Report on Endowed Funds, 2001-2002 (Box 106, Folder 46)
  - Report on Endowed Funds (Box 106, Folder 47)
  - Report on Endowed Funds, 2003-2004 (Box 106, Folder 48)
  - Newsletter-"E-cology", 2000-2005 (Box 105, Folder 55)
  - Brief Historical Observations by Francille Firebaugh and Jean Robinson, 2004 (Box 106, Folder 52)
  - Web pages from Human Ecology's website, 1999 (Box 70, Folder 28)
  - Web pages from the Early Childhood Center at Cornell website, 2007 (Box 70, Folder 29)
  - Web pages from Human Ecology's website under "College Governance", 2006-08 (Box 88, Folder 20)
  - Web pages from Human Ecology's website under "Research", 2006-2007 (Box 70, Folder 31)
  - Didactic Program in Dietetics - Dietetic Internship - Self-Study 1, 2001-04 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Didactic Program in Dietetics - Dietetic Internship - Self-Study 2, 2001 (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Division of Nutritional Sciences, Self-Study 1, 1999-05 (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Division of Nutritional Sciences, Self-Study 2, 1999 (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Division of Nutritional Sciences Volume 2, Self-Study 3, 1999 (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Division of Nutritional Sciences, Volume 2, Self-Study 4, 1999 (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Division of Nutritional Sciences, Volume 2, Self-Study 5, 1999 (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - Division of Nutritional Sciences, Volume 2, Self-Study 6, 1999 (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - Division of Nutritional Sciences, Volume 3, Self-Study 7, 1999 (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - Division of Nutritional Sciences, Volume 3, Self-Study 8, 1999 (Box 103, Folder 10)
  - Division of Nutritional Sciences, Volume 3, Self-Study 9, 1999 (Box 103, Folder 11)
  - Brochures, pamphlets, publications, programs, pertaining to various college events and exhibits and describing the programs and departments in the college (ARP), 1968-2017 (Box 107-109)
- Series XI: Facility Records
  - Master Plans for the College, 1975-1985 (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Campus Master Plan-Response to the SUNY Master Plan, 1980 (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Master Plan- MVR, 1988-1991 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - East Wing/Nursery Wing Renovations, 1988-2000 (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - Master Plan- GRI Project, 1991-1994 (Box 122, Folder 3)
  - Master Plan- MVR, 1992-1994 (Box 122, Folder 4)
  - Master Plan- MVR, 1992-2003 (Box 122, Folder 5)
  - West Wing Addition, 1992-2001 (Box 122, Folder 6)
  - West Wing Addition- Equipment and Furnishings, 1992-2001 (Box 122, Folder 7)
  - North Wing Floors, 1992-2002 (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - Master Plan Phase One Program Report, 1994 (Box 70, Folder 23)
  - Summary of Completed Renovations, 1993 (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - Restrooms Renovations- Schematic Design Report, 1997-04, 1998-03 (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - Master Plan- MVR, 1999-2000 (Box 122, Folder 8)
  - Textiles and Apparel Lab Construction, 2000 (Box 122, Folder 9)
  - Nutrition Transgenic Mouse Facility, 2001 (Box 122, Folder 10)
  - Consultant's Report for the Renovation of MVR Hall, 2000? (Box 106, Folder 51)
  - Nutrition Transgenic Mouse Facility Report, 2001-05 (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - Transgenic Mouse Facilities, 2003-2006 (Box 118, Folder 21)
  - Initial Structural Investigation and Evaluation of Concrete Floor Slabs Report- MVR Hall-North Wing, 2001-08 (Box 118, Folder 4)
  - North Wing Replacement, 2001-2003 (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - North MVR Surge Plan, 2002-2004 (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - North MVR Conception, 2002-2006 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Feasibility Report, 2002-01 (Box 118, Folder 5)
  - Animal Care and Use Program- Review, 2002-05 (Box 118, Folder 6)
  - Assessment of Laboratory Animal Facilities- Savage and MVR Halls, 2002-06 (Box 118, Folder 7)
  - Chilled Water Study, 2002-10 (Box 118, Folder 8)
  - Demolition and Construction of a New Addition to MVR Hall-Presentation and Statements of Qualifications- Arquitectonica, 2002 (Box 118, Folder 9)
  - MVR North Parking Garage Feasibility Study- Sasaki Associates, 2003-05 (Box 118, Folder 10)
  - Cornell Management System for the Environment and Chemical Management- Work Plan, 2002-08 (Box 118, Folder 11)
  - Animal Facility Feasibility Study- Kinzelberg Hall, 2003-11 (Box 118, Folder 12)
  - Kinzelberg Hall Feasibility Study, 1999-2000 (Box 122, Folder 11)
  - North MVR Talking Points- Steve Johnson, 2003-08-20 (Box 121, Folder 5)
  - North MVR Site Criteria, 2003 (Box 121, Folder 6)
  - Budget - Replacement Building, 2003-2008 (Box 121, Folder 7)
  - Master Plan for Replacement North MVR, 2001-2008 (Box 121, Folder 8)
  - Student Commons Design, 2003-2006 (Box 122, Folder 12)
  - MVR renovation meeting, 2004 (Box 118, Folder 22)
  - Master Planning for Replacement North MVR, 2004-03-2004-10 (Box 121, Folder 9)
  - Master Planning for Replacement North MVR, 2004-11-2006 (Box 121, Folder 10)
  - Architects' Meetings, 2003-2004 (Box 121, Folder 11)
  - Temporary Certificate of Occupancy MVR Basement, 2004 (Box 122, Folder 13)
  - Temporary Certificate of Occupancy Martha's, 2004 (Box 122, Folder 14)
  - Architects' Meetings, 2005 (Box 121, Folder 12)
  - Architects' Meetings, 2006-2007-03 (Box 121, Folder 13)
  - Architects' Meetings, 2007-04-2010 (Box 121, Folder 14)
  - North MVR Steering Committee Meetings, 2004-2005 (Box 121, Folder 15-17)
  - Opening of "Martha's", 2004 (Box 121, Folder 18)
  - North MVR Demolition, 2005 (Box 121, Folder 19)
  - North MVR Demolition Town Meeting, 2005 (Box 121, Folder 20)
  - Vivarium Expansion Project- CUH2A Qualifications, 2004-09 (Box 118, Folder 13)
  - MVR Hall-North Replacement- Gruzen Sampton Architects-Presentation, 2005-04 (Box 118, Folder 14)
  - Urban Semester Renovation Plans, 2005 (Box 122, Folder 15)
  - Early Childhood Facility, 2005-2006 (Box 122, Folder 16)
  - Facilities Function Analysis and Project Plan, 2006-03 (Box 118, Folder 15)
  - MVR Hall- North Replacement Schematic Design Report, 2006-10 (Box 118, Folder 16, 17)
  - North MVR Architects Presentation, 2006-01 (Box 121, Folder 21)
  - North MVR Programming and Adjacencies, 2006 (Box 121, Folder 22)
  - North MVR Schedule, 2006 (Box 121, Folder 23)
  - Gallery and Commons Considerations, 2006 (Box 121, Folder 24)
  - Human Ecology Center for Science and Design, 2006 (Box 121, Folder 25)
  - North MVR VJ Associates Concept Estimate, 2006-03 (Box 121, Folder 26)
  - Nutriton Master Facility Planning Program, 2006 (Box 118, Folder 23)
  - DNS Master Programming Study, 2007-05 (Box 118, Folder 24)
  - Master Plan Working Committee, 2006-2007 (Box 122, Folder 17-19)
  - Organization and Function Analysis, 2006 (Box 122, Folder 20)
  - Emergency Preparedness, 2006-2008 (Box 122, Folder 21)
  - Bids, 2007-2008 (Box 121, Folder 27)
  - Land Ownership, 2007 (Box 121, Folder 28)
  - Displays - Human Ecology Building, 2007 (Box 121, Folder 29)
  - Gallery, 2007 (Box 121, Folder 30)
  - MVR Rehab - Identify Space Requirements for AV, 2007 (Box 122, Folder 22)
  - MVR 1933 Building Renovation - Budget, 2007 (Box 122, Folder 23)
  - MVR 1933 Building Renovation - Design, 2008 (Box 122, Folder 24)
  - Facilities renovation and surge activities, policies, changing paradigm, 2007-2009 (Box 118, Folder 25)
  - MRI Facility at Cornell, 2007-2009 (Box 122, Folder 25)
  - MRI Facility - NIH Grant, 2009 (Box 122, Folder 26)
  - Environmental Health and Safety College Issues, 2008 (Box 122, Folder 27)
  - LEED Certification, 2008 (Box 121, Folder 31)
  - Commons, 2009-2010 (Box 121, Folder 32)
  - Time Capsule - Human Ecology Building, 2010-2011 (Box 121, Folder 33)
  - Human Factors Lab, 2010 (Box 121, Folder 34)
  - Classroom space management, 2010-2013 (Box 118, Folder 26)
  - Dedication - Human Ecology Building, 2011-10-20 (Box 121, Folder 35)
  - Human Ecology Building Project, 2011-10 (Box 118, Folder 18)
  - Human Ecology Building Brochures, 2011 (Box 118, Folder 19)
  - Emerging Activities with HEB (Human Ecology Building) and MVR Renovation Project, 2011 (Box 105, Folder 56)
  - Human Ecology Building Opening, 2012-01 (Box 118, Folder 20)
  - Developing a transformable classroom, an academic and administrative project with student led design, 2014 (Box 118, Folder 27)
  - Oversized sketches of the front of MVR Hall, some on mylar, undated (Box 120)
- Series XII: Memorabilia
  - Distinguished Teaching Award Plaque, 1979-1990; MU-1548 (Box 72)
  - Silver Tray given to Jean Robinson for Dean's Distinguished Service Award, 1996; MU-1549 (Box 72)
  - Silver Tray given to Alice Davey, 1958-1987; MU-1550 (Box 72)
  - Hand Marbled Artwork by Ashley Miller used as background for various college publications, 1989 (Folder Oversized)
  - Large plastic banner with college name and seal (Box 73)
  - Coaster given at dedication of West addition in MVR Hall, 2002-11-01; MU-1155
  - Martha's Opening Memorabilia - mug, apron, chocolate bar wrapping, flyer, 2004-06-23; MU-1167 (Box 76)
  - Pin from closing of North MVR Hall, 2001; MU-1544 (Box 76)
  - Note cards picturing Martha Van Rensselaer Hall, MU-1545 (Box 76)
  - Pin from the Party on the Terrace and College Update, 2011-05-17; MU-1546 (Box 76)
  - Four T-shirts from various College events, including the dedication of the Human Ecology Building, 2011-2016; MU-1701-1704 (Box 124)
  - Ribbon from the dedication of the Human Ecology Building, 2011-10-20; MU-2734 (Box 76)
  - T-shirt distributed when demolition of MVR Hall took place, 2005; MU-2733 (Box 124)
  - Pin from ice cream social in the courtyard, 2012-05-03; MU-1547 (Box 76)
  - Pin commemorating Cornell Cooperative Extension Centennial, 2011; MU-2752 (Box 76)
  - Silver tray, engraved on bottom: "College of Home Economics, 1931", MU-2845 (Box 133)
  - Sample of marbled paper (Map-case Folder 1)
- Series XIII. Conferences, Symposiums, Institutes
  - Obesity Conference Poster (Box MS Box 41)
  - Household Time Use: Research in the 21st Century-Conference, 1992 (Box 70, Folder 26)
  - Symposiums, 1983-1985 (Box 70, Folder 15)
  - 65th Anniversary Institute, 1990 (Box 70, Folder 25)
  - Iscol Family Program in Leadership in Public Service, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 32)
  - Ecology of Obesity list of attendees, conference information, posters, publicity, 2005-06-06-2005-06-07 (Box 88, Folder 21)
- Series XIV. Curriculum/Theses Titles
  - Advanced Degree List, 1980-1994 (Box 105, Folder 41)
  - Curriculum Task Group, 1982 (Box 70, Folder 15)
  - Multicultural Content in the Human Ecology Curriculum, 1995 (Box 105, Folder 26)
  - Theses and Dissertation Titles, 2004-2005 (Box 91)
  - Curriculum Sheets, 1999-2011 (Box 91)